# Mikail Duzenli

**Nationality:** French (+33) 0603720218 **Date of birth:** 25/04/1998

**Email address:** <u>duzenlimikail@gmail.com</u> **⊕ Website:** <u>https://github.com/MikailINTech</u>

**Q** Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/mikailduzenli in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mikailduzenli/

• Address: 32 Rue des Dragons, 91240 Saint-Michel-sur-Orge (France)

#### **ABOUT ME**

Double graduate with a major in data science experienced in both research and industry with high-responsibility assignments. Autonomy and problem-solving skills proven by successful results in recent experience or personal projects. Motivated to apply knowledge of machine learning to a meaningful project as a Data scientist.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Research internship in Machine Learning for medical images**

*Inria* [ 04/2022 – 10/2022 ]

**City:** Gif-sur-Yvette **Country:** France

- Studied state-of-the-art Deep Learning approaches to generate realistic data from simulated data: VAEs, GANs
- Proposed the appropriate solutions collaborating with the partner company's R&D team.
- Developed the chosen models in Python (TensorFlow) and tracked them with Git.
- Evaluation and analysis of results through meetings: the final result is a 10% boost in the performance of their product.

<u>Developed skills</u>: Python, Numpy, TensorFlow, Git, Docker, Linux

## **Computer vision engineer Research & Development internship**

**Safran Electronics & Defense** [ 02/2021 - 08/2021 ]

City: Massy
Country: France

- Studied the multi-object tracking problems (MOT).
- Developed Kalman filters and related algorithms in MATLAB.
- Simulated synthetic scenarios to assess the developed methods then analyzed results on field data.
- Improved the results of the method by 33% by proposing the appropriate modifications.

Developed skills: Matlab

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# Master of Science (M.S.) - Artificial Intelligence (AI)

**Paris Dauphine - PSL** [ 09/2021 – 09/2022 ]

Address: 75016 Paris

https://www.lamsade.dauphine.fr/wp/iasd/ Field(s) of study: Artificial Intelligence (AI)

<u>Courses</u>: Machine learning, Deep learning, Reinforcement learning, Optimization, Advanced databases, Computer vision, NLP, Monte Carlo Tree search, and 3D point clouds.

Developed skills: Python, Numpy, Keras, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Git, PySpark, SQL

## **Engineer's Degree - Math and Statistics**

**Télécom SudParis** [ 09/2018 – 09/2021 ]

Address: 91000 Evry (France)

https://www.telecom-sudparis.eu/formation/modelisations-statistiques-et-applications/

Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies

Relevant courses: Statistics, Machine learning, Deep learning, Signal processing, Data science, Computer science.

Developed skills: Python, R, Keras, Numpy, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Git, SQL, Linux, C/C++

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): French

Other language(s):

### **English**

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING C2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1** 

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

### **My Digital Skills**

Deep Learning / Data Science / Artificial Intelligence / Machine Learning / Computer Vision / Coding / Modeling / Analytics / NLP / programming / Data analytics

### **PROJECTS**

### Tabular Playground Series - Sep 2022 (Final rank: 13/1363)

One example from the competitions I participated in on Kaggle:

- The goal was to forecast sales during the tumultuous year 2021 for "Kaggle merchandise stores" datasets.
- The difficulty lied in the data analytics part when conditions are far from the ordinary.

### Training of a point cloud Transformer model in PyTorch with GCP

One example from the projects I developed at school (you can find them on my Github):

- The objective of this project was to delve into the point cloud segmentation problem.
- The particular structure of point clouds can be more adequately captured by the attention mechanisms of Transformer models.

#### **Vision Transformer Gradio Demo**

*My first gradio demo* as I started to contribute to open source:

- Built a demo where a pre-trained model predicts missing words in a sentence and added some useful visualization.
- Collaborated with developers on Github to solve issues and deliver qualitative content.